## Ivo Gatzinski

San Diego, CA 92122 | ivo.gatzinski@outlook.com | 619-352-0538

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ivo-gatzinski/ Portfolio: https://ivo-gatzinski.github.io/portfolio/

GitHub: https://github.com/Ivo-Gatzinski/

#### **Summary**

Multilingual, multicultural, multidisciplinary Full Stack Web Developer with three years of experience. Collaborative, attentive, and compassionate listener who meets concrete needs of diverse viewpoints. Sensitive to others' perspectives, having lived in six countries on four continents. Fluent in Bulgarian and Russian; moderate French; basic Japanese. Earned Certificate in Full Stack Web Design by UCSD. (Grade: A)

#### **Competencies**

- Languages: JavaScript, CSS, HTML
- Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, IndexedDB, Apollo, GraphQL
- Frameworks: React.js, Handlebars.js, Node.js, Express.js, Mongoose.js, Sequelize.js

### Projects (2021)

"Healthy Pets" - Vet & Pet communication portal.

- Tools: JavaScript, React.js, GraphQL, Apollo, MongoDB, Module.CSS, HTML
- GitHub: https://github.com/elenaliu0415/healthy-pets/
- Deployed App: <a href="https://healthy-pets-copypaste.herokuapp.com/">https://healthy-pets-copypaste.herokuapp.com/</a>

"Magic 8 Ball" - Combat decision fatigue!

- Tools: JavaScript, MySQL, Handlebars.js, MDBootstrap CSS, HTML
- GitHub: https://github.com/Ivo-Gatzinski/magic-8-ball/
- Deployed App: <a href="https://magic8-ezi.herokuapp.com/">https://magic8-ezi.herokuapp.com/</a>

"Adopt a Furry Buddy" - Search for Adoptable Dogs.

- Tools: JavaScript, Server-Side APIs, CSS, HTML
- GitHub: https://github.com/Ivo-Gatzinski/adoption-connection/
- Deployed App: https://ivo-gatzinski.github.io/adoption-connection/

### **Experience**

Adjunct Faculty in Political Science

Miramar College Department of Political Science, San Diego, CA

2019-Present

- Taught U.S. government, introductory and comparative politics, theory, economics, social science research, and academic writing via individual tutoring, on-site, hybrid, and online instruction, using various online learning platforms, such as Blackboard, Canvas, Aplia, Connect, etc.
- Tutored diverse students to enable holistic growth in learning capacities
- Designed active learning strategies for investigating politics and society objectively

Adjunct Faculty in Economics

Southwestern College Department of Economics, Chula Vista, CA

2016-2017

Taught economics, and relevant social science research, academic writing, reading, and math skills

Tutor in Social Sciences, Humanities, and ESL

Grossmont College Tutoring Center, El Cajon, CA

2013-2016

- Coached diverse students in economics, sociology, political science, history, research, and writing
- Responded with sensitivity and compassion to coordinate accessibility accommodations
- Taught interdisciplinary material clearly and accessibly to diverse learners and audiences
- Collaborated with staff and faculty to design and administer tutoring services and workshops

• Tutored diverse ESL students in academic writing, English, social sciences, and basic math skills

# Adjunct Faculty in Political Science

### Grossmont College Department of Political Economy

2013-2016

- Taught U.S. government, introductory and comparative politics, theory, economics, social science research, and academic writing via individual tutoring, on-site, hybrid, and online instruction, using various online learning platforms, such as Blackboard, Canvas, Aplia, Connect, etc.
- Tutored diverse students to enable holistic growth in learning capacities
- Constructed and applied criteria to measure, assess, monitor, and report student learning outcomes
- Engaged diverse learners and audiences by translating complex ideas and academic research clearly and accessibly into ordinary language in lectures, seminars, and workshops
- Designed active learning strategies for investigating politics and society objectively
- Resolved misinterpretations, complaints, conflicts, and cultural frictions between diverse students, responding with sensitivity and compassion to complex needs

## Adjunct Faculty in Sociology & Political Science National University

2013-2017

- Taught sociology of gender, race, class, economics, and family; social theory; introduction to sociology; introduction to politics, comparative politics, U.S. government; social science research design, on-site, hybrid, and online, with variety of learning platforms, e.g. Blackboard, eCollege, Canvas, etc.
- Met unique needs of working adult veterans from complex and diverse backgrounds
- Mediated verbal and body-language misunderstandings from diverse student viewpoints
- Clearly explicated complex material for working adults in highly accelerated, intensive curriculum
- Facilitated respectful, fluid discussions for the scientific study of sensitive political and social topics
- Compiled and used various criteria, databases, platforms to measure and evaluate learning outcomes

#### **Teaching Assistant**

## Roosevelt College MMW Writing Curriculum, UC San Diego

2007-2015

- Taught academic writing, scholarly research, humanities, and social sciences to undergraduates via individual and group workshops, seminars, and hybrid instruction with various learning platforms
- Trained students in all aspects of scholarly research and academic writing, attending carefully to diverse needs to enable growth of learning capacities, writing skills, and critical thinking
- Diagnosed student needs to design active learning strategies for individual tutoring and seminars
- Collaborated closely with diverse team to evaluate and improve procedures and criteria for teaching, tutoring, and program services, for a multi-cultural, liberal arts curriculum in world civilizations
- Met unique needs of students from diverse linguistic, cultural, academic, and personal backgrounds, including English language learners and students transferring from community colleges
- Created, evaluated, enhanced, and implemented precise, highly structured writing assignments
- Constructed and evaluated criteria for measuring and assessing student learning outcomes

## **Teaching Assistant**

## Department of Political Science, UC San Diego

2003-2007

- Taught comparative politics and theory, history, religion, urban development, ethics, and sociology
- Trained wide range of students in plural methodologies for interdisciplinary research design
- Distilled and translated political science and sociology into ordinary language for diverse audiences

#### **Education**

• Certificate in Full Stack Web Development – UCSD Bootcamp 2021

Doctor of Philosophy Candidate in Political Science – UC San Diego
Master's in Political Science – UC San Diego
2003-2012
2005

Bachelor's in Economics – Amherst College, Magna Cum Laude, Phi Beta Kappa
2002